hi, welcome back to the channel again.
there’s an issue here
I’ve passed a hundred subscribers and I’m quite happy about
but I kept having to look at the website every time
I wanted to see how many people are there
In the channel, to see how many people have subscribed
And I would like to automate this
So I looked at the API that google provides
and I just want to write a small
script in Perl
To fetch the data and do something with that
the first thing I do is download the strawberry Perl
as usual
So I go to the website padre.perlide.org
uh... click on the download link and
there I get to the padre on strawberry
package that has
both strawberry Perl padre IDE
and some other stuff there
Once I install, I run it
Strawberry Perl
padre and I’ll have the editor ready
And that’s great. Well, obviously that’s not enough
I’ll have to start writing it so
Perl script
because I prefer to
write some modern Perl
Change it to number version known as
twenties, that was a bit too much but
I’ll start with Perl 5.10
And I saved the script
Lets call it youtube.pl
Now that doesn’t do anything yet
We have to... we need some kind of
code to get there to get to youtube channel
And the way to do that is not
to write my own
access to the API but to go to
assertion directories
So I’ll go to metacpan.org
which is a new assertion directories
See, it says beta
But I think they can get rid of this beta.
They are not google’s
So it can run a service without
being beta for like five years
Anyway, this is a search engine
and we are trying to access youtube
so I type in “youtube”
and it’ll give me
various results
So I don’t know what the text is.
It’s probably irrelevant for me
and there is a web service youtube
that’s interesting
uh... so let’s see what does that do
i clicked on that one
it says uh... “This module only supports Legacy API”
that’s not what we want so let’s go
back and look further
Lets see this one, it’s pretty old
And lets see this one. Well...
This is quite new, lets see... what does this do.
It says WebService GData YouTube
That’s the API version too... that sounds OK.
“Developer release, API may change...” that sound good
I like code that actually tells that
i can write it uh... use it and then
it will break
So lets download and install it.
The way we can do it
is uh... take uh...
the name of the module
then we go to the start menu
And Strawberry Perl... tools...
and then there’s the CPan client
Which is not working
Oh, because i already have one... so i
Already have one open
what you need to do is install
install
and then copy paste the name of the
module
and once you run this and press enter
it will download the module and install it
actually in mine it’s already
Installed. Scroll up and you
will see it’s running, it’s running the tasks
And the unit test of the module
and that they are installed
so once it’s installed I quit this so i
won’t get this problem
next time, that
It doesn’t start
and let’s start to write the code
what i can see when i go to the
synopsis and
Lets just make some copy-paste here
So I’ll load this, sorry.
I load the the module itself to memory
I need to create an object like this
uh... actually this is using a lot of
An indirect method call
That’s not really recommended to use
it so instead of putting the new
key word here
which is not really a keyword, it’s a
method
Call, I put it
this way
i think is better
So I created the object $yt which is
The youtube object
and then the top-rated videos
that’s not interesting for me
what i would like to know to get, lets see...
get user
“get user profile” here, so this is
what i need: “get user profile”
so i just type in
$yt get user profile
and then it says
uh... optionally i can give the name of
the user or i have to be logged in
I won’t be logged in, so
I just type here the username I have on youtube
and
That will return me the profile in this variable hopefully
And it will return this user profile
Instantly, so lets see what’s in there
and it has information about
me for example
so let’s say
about
and lets run this now, I press F5
to run this code
And it says international Perl trainer and speaker
and yeah, that’s good
so that’s my uh
about whatever it’s called
In neutral terms
and so great, that’s working. That’s good
But it will change, you know
uh... and then uh... let’s see what else
can i get
statistics or probably i need the statistics
uh... lets put it here
so i get the profile from the profile i
get the statistics
so from the profile, statistics
Right, this is how it’s spelled, yeah
and there I can print out
the
from the statistics I can see
there if you count for example
View count
And lets see, run this again
this goes to youtube
And checks the data... and that’s view count
That’s probably right
uh... and that’s the total number
of views of the channel
at subscriber account
OK, so... although it is better to copy-paste
so I won’t make too many
Typos... so this is the...
subscriber count and then
Video watch count
this is i don’t know why there is a
space here but
lets see... video watch count
that’s probably the total count any
of my videos have been...
Seen or watched or whatever. I press F5.
and uh...
No that gives me zero... probably not right
uh... but a hundred is good so
there’re a hundred subscribers
Oh, so total upload views so that would be
The right one
except that it has spaces here I don’t
if it’s displayed incorrectly
all of the data of the code or
actually there’s is a typo in there
In documentation
so uh... i copy-pasted it and it has underscores there
so...
it must be there
display
So, if I... I don’t need this
video watch counter, I don’t know what’s
that, it was zero for me
and here we are, almost twenty
thousand, we need a couple of more people
and then
it’s gonna be
over that number
So, okay, so i have all this data
and uh what should I do with it?
so let’s say... I send myself an email
So, lets send an email
uh... how do i do that so I go back to
place and uh...
so i don’t want to send it to gmail
So I type in Gmail to search for a module
IMAPD, that’s not what I want
Checker, no
gmail smpt gmail
that sounds good
okay so lets copy-paste this one
I don’t have to install it, because I already did
you have to install it
Anyway, so I clicked on the link and
so this is the guy who wrote it
I don’t know if... yeah anyway
So, here is synopsis, how I need to use it
so use the module
to go to memory, connect to the server’s
login and password
and then
Well, I just sent an email so
let’s copy-paste this one
uh...
yeah your
and then I need the adress
is gmail and uh... login
i’m going to use this login adress
five two nine
uh... and then the password... well this is
the password at google
google and me
uh... and then i’m going to send it to
myself so it’s gmail
It’s
gabor529
so the subject is youtube
update
Verbose, okay let’s be verbose and the
text so the text should be so let’s put
a variable called text here
and and and an attachment
I don’t have an attachment theory yet so
lets comment this out
and this was a text
the text
should be declared here
this is going to be the text of the
of my email
right here, so I write
So, lets see...
view count
Actually it’s not good
If your document right now so
let’s put it like this
and then, say text
that’s okay that’s not
correct, text
view count
view comment and then I concatenate
the...
view count here
and then
concatenate a newline... right
and
So I put here... subscribers
I put here, this is the
subscriber count
and what else do I need to add?
the last one so the last one
than last one is the views
total
total views
umm, I get
total upload views
so... yeah
that’s the text hopefully
and this is not needed anymore
so that’s hopefully will send me
An email
Lets run this... F5
and it’s says
for some reason it says attachments
successfully verified even though i don’t
have an attachment and the mail sent
okay so let’s switch over to my
gmail inbox and here we are i’ve just
got the email from myself
about the fact that
I have a hundred subscribers
so that’s great i think and I
could just add the
scheduler over those
and then have it run
every five minutes let’s say
to make sure that uh...
my numbers are growing
Or once a day, if I’m not that crazy
Anyway, I hope that now I will have a lot more subscribers
So go ahead and subscribe to my channel
And let anyone else know that they should
Bye bye!